Nader Salam

IT Manager



ABOUT ME

IT Manager with 16 years experience, working in MENA, Africa and India. Exceptional skill with full stack programming, Computer networks and organizing workshops for AI.

Effectively plan, configure, and optimize IT infrastructure to consistently achieve high availability and performance.

Well versed in AI fields like Computer Vision, Deep Learning and Machine Learning.

Skilled in Software Engineering methodologies, tools and techniques

Get in Touch

- 🔀 nader684@yahoo.co.in
- +91-7902983757
- mader-salam-92479795

EDUCATION

Research Scholar (Ph.D) in CSE (2021)

Karunya Institute of Technology and Sciences

Currently doing my PhD as a research scholar in Artificial Intelligence. CGPA - 8.43

MTECH in CSE (2017)

Kerala University

Completed MTECH in CSE with a CGPA score of 8.58

EXPERIENCE

Now Prepay Mozambique S.A.

IT Manager (2015-2021)

Designed, Developed and Implemented E-payment Platform NPAYE.

Integration with Electricity, Water, Gas, and Cable TV Providers within the country was overseen successfully

Mint Electronic Payment Services, Dubai

Senior IT Engineer (2013-2015)

Designed, Developed and Implemented Web Portals for E-payment.

Managed and Maintained Qcomm and Efresh Sustems

Global Business Services, Dubai

Senior IT Engineer (2010-2013)

Designed, Developed and Implemented Web Portals using Liferay with Eclipse Juno.

Publications

Masked RCNN+ fast boosted tree classifier: for neural networks

and classifier for pedestrian detection

DOI https://dl.acm.org/doi/10.1145/3339311.3339317

ACM Digital

COVID-19 Risk Prediction with Regularized Discriminant Analysis and Lasso Regression using Booster Tree

DOI https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-19-0095-2

Springer Singapore

Personal Dossier

Date of Birth: 6th Sep 1984

Nationality : Indian

Passport No : Z4765030

Marital Status : Married

License : UAE, India and

Mozambique

Languages: English, Hindi,

Malaualam, Arabic

Achievements

Presented paper Masked RCNN+
fast boosted tree classifier: for
neural networks and classifier for
pedestrian detection in Advanced
Informatics for Computing
Research Third International
Conference, ICAICR 2019

Presented paper COVID-19 Risk
Prediction with Regularized
Discriminant Analysis and Lasso
Regression Using Booster Tree in
Sixth International Conference on
Information and Communication
Technology for Competitive
Strategies (ICTCS-2021)

Projects and

Repositories

https://nadertodocli.herokuapp.com/.

https://ec2-15-207-55-154.ap-

south-

1.compute.amazonaws.com/admin 2/login.php.

https://github.com/redan684

Expertise

Full Stack Development

Back-end Development

Front-end Development

Project Management

Research

MY SKILLS



Python/Django



Java



MySql



Tensor Flow



Android



React



Oracle

Hobbies









Reading

Basketball

Hiking

Music